{
  "theme": [
    {
      "Questions": [
        {
          "Question": "What was the first animated Disney film?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Cinderella",
            "Beauty and the Beast",
            "Tangled"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs was released in 1937, marking the start of Disney's animation legacy."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which '90s sitcom features a group of friends living in New York City?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Friends",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Seinfeld",
            "The Fresh Prince of Bel-Air",
            "That '70s Show"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Friends, which aired from 1994 to 2004, remains a pop culture phenomenon with memorable characters and iconic catchphrases."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who directed the 1985 film 'The Goonies'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Richard Donner",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Steven Spielberg",
            "George Lucas",
            "Robert Zemeckis"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Richard Donner directed 'The Goonies', a beloved adventure film that has maintained a cult following since its release."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which fictional character served as the host of 'Mister Rogers' Neighborhood'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Fred Rogers",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Bob Ross",
            "Barney the Dinosaur",
            "Big Bird"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Fred Rogers, known for his gentle and compassionate nature, brought comfort and joy to millions of viewers through his beloved show."
        },
        {
          "Question": "In what year was the first 'Pokémon' video game released?",
          "TrueAnswer": "1996",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "2000",
            "1999",
            "1994"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The original 'Pokémon' Red and Green versions were released for the Game Boy in Japan in 1996, igniting a cultural phenomenon."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which movie starred the characters Buzz Lightyear and Woody?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Toy Story",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The Lion King",
            "Finding Nemo",
            "Shrek"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'Toy Story' (1995) marked the beginning of Pixar's dominance in animated films, captivating audiences with its innovative storytelling and lovable characters."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who directed the 1984 supernatural comedy 'Ghostbusters'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Ivan Reitman",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Tim Burton",
            "John Hughes",
            "Spike Lee"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Ivan Reitman helmed 'Ghostbusters', a film that blended humor, scares, and cutting-edge special effects to become a timeless classic."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which '90s boy band dominated the pop music scene?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Backstreet Boys",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "NSYNC",
            "Hanson",
            "98 Degrees"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The Backstreet Boys, with hits like 'I Want It That Way', became one of the best-selling music groups of all time during the late 1990s."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What is the iconic slogan of the '90s TV show 'The X-Files'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "The Truth Is Out There",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "I Want to Believe",
            "Trust No One",
            "Deny Everything"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The catchphrase 'The Truth Is Out There' encapsulated the mysterious and enigmatic nature of 'The X-Files', a sci-fi phenomenon of the '90s."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which '80s TV series featured the iconic line 'I pity the fool'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "The A-Team",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Knight Rider",
            "Miami Vice",
            "Magnum, P.I."
          ],
          "Explanation": "Mr. T as B.A. Baracus popularized the catchphrase 'I pity the fool' in 'The A-Team', an action-packed TV show loved by '80s audiences."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who voiced the character Simba in the animated movie 'The Lion King' (1994)?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Matthew Broderick",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Jonathan Taylor Thomas",
            "Jeremy Irons",
            "James Earl Jones"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Matthew Broderick provided the voice for adult Simba, adding his charm and charisma to the beloved character in 'The Lion King'."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What toy became a cultural phenomenon in the '80s with its colorful blocks?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Legos",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rubik's Cube",
            "Cabbage Patch Kids",
            "Transformers"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Legos, with their endless creativity and versatility, captured the imaginations of children worldwide and became a beloved pop culture icon."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which animated TV series featured the adventurous SpongeBob SquarePants?",
          "TrueAnswer": "SpongeBob SquarePants",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Rugrats",
            "The Powerpuff Girls",
            "Dexter's Laboratory"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'SpongeBob SquarePants', created by Stephen Hillenburg, became a timeless favorite for its humor, quirky characters, and catchy theme song."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What iconic dance move was popularized by Michael Jackson in the '80s?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Moonwalk",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Dougie",
            "Floss",
            "Robot"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The 'Moonwalk', a signature move of Michael Jackson, captivated audiences worldwide with its smooth and gravity-defying style."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Who portrayed the teenage witch Sabrina in the '90s TV show 'Sabrina the Teenage Witch'?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Melissa Joan Hart",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Emma Watson",
            "Alyssa Milano",
            "Tiffany Amber Thiessen"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Melissa Joan Hart brought the magical world of Sabrina Spellman to life, charming audiences with her wit and relatable teenage dilemmas."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What arcade game introduced the famous character Pac-Man in 1980?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Puck-Man",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Donkey Kong",
            "Space Invaders",
            "Centipede"
          ],
          "Explanation": "Puck-Man, later changed to Pac-Man for the Western release, revolutionized the gaming industry and became a global pop culture phenomenon."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which '80s film showcased the iconic dance scene featuring Patrick Swayze and Jennifer Grey?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Dirty Dancing",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Footloose",
            "Flashdance",
            "Fame"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'Dirty Dancing' is celebrated for its romantic storyline and memorable dance sequences, solidifying its status as a nostalgic classic."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which movie series features time travel in a DeLorean car?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Back to the Future",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The Terminator",
            "Bill & Ted's Excellent Adventure",
            "Hot Tub Time Machine"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'Back to the Future' captivated audiences with its entertaining time-travel plot, beloved characters, and the iconic DeLorean car."
        },
        {
          "Question": "What Nintendo game cartridge contained multiple classic games in the '80s?",
          "TrueAnswer": "Super Mario Bros./Duck Hunt",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "The Legend of Zelda",
            "Metroid",
            "Mega Man"
          ],
          "Explanation": "The 'Super Mario Bros./Duck Hunt' cartridge offered two beloved games in one, providing players with hours of nostalgic gaming fun."
        },
        {
          "Question": "Which '90s TV show explored paranormal phenomena and government conspiracies?",
          "TrueAnswer": "The X-Files",
          "FalseAnswer": [
            "Buffy the Vampire Slayer",
            "Twin Peaks",
            "Millennium"
          ],
          "Explanation": "'The X-Files' delved into the unknown, blending science fiction, horror, and drama, and became a cultural touchstone of the '90s."
        }
      ]
    }
  ]
}